Guide to the Boone and Crockett Club Records circa 1885-2009
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Foundation, 1982-2005; Series V; 9.5 linear feet
  - Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Ranch, 1982-2005; Subseries 3; 3.25 linear feet
    - Correspondence and Reports, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 202/1)
    - Correpondence, Memoranda, and Reports, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 202/2-3)
    - Conservation Easement, The Nature Conservancy, 1990-2003 (Box-folder 225/7)
    - Deed of Conservation Easement, The Nature Conservancy, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 202/4)
    - Deed of Conservation Easement, The Nature Conservancy, 2001 (Box-folder 227/2)
    - Description and Purchase, Correspondence and Reports, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 202/5)
    - Donation and Expense Summaries, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 202/6)
    - Donation and Financial Documents, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 202/7)
    - Donation Data, 1986 (Box-folder 202/8)
    - Donations and Pledges, 1985 (Box-folder 202/9)
    - Donations and Pledges, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 203/1-2)
    - Donations and Pledges, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 203/3)
    - Donations Committee, Correspondence and Memorandum, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 203/4)
    - Donor Correspondence and Lists, 1985 (Box-folder 203/5)
    - Early Selection Sites, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 203/6)
    - Education Research Facility Project manual, 1999 (Box-folder 203/7-8)
    - Elk Monitoring Project, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 203/9)
    - Environmental Issues, 1987 (Box-folder 203/10)
    - Expenses, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 203/11)
    - Financial Report, 1990 (Box-folder 203/12)
    - Funding Objectives, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 203/13)
    - Funding Objectives and Program Memorandum, 1988 (Box-folder 204/1)
    - Fundraising, Action List, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 204/2)
    - Fundraising, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 204/3)
    - Fundraising, Meeting Materials, 1985 (Box-folder 204/4)
    - Grant-in-aid Proposal, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 204/5)
    - Grant-in-aid Proposals, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 204/6-7)
    - Fisher Howe Feasibility Study, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 204/8)
    - Issues and Problems, Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 204/9)
    - Mailer to Contributors, 1989 (Box-folder 204/10)
    - Map, Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 204/11)
    - Master Memoranda of Understanding Between the Boone and Crockett Club and the United States Department of Agriculture Forest Service, undated (Box-folder 205/1)
    - Matters Discussed in Executive Committee Minutes, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 205/2)
    - Membership and Sponsorship Lists, 1985 (Box-folder 205/3)
    - Membership, Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 205/4)
    - Nature Conservancy, Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 205/5)
    - Operations and Capital Expenditures Budget, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 205/6)
    - Operations Budget, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 205/7)
    - Organizational Proposals and Inquiries, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 205/8)
    - Original Forms, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 205/9)
    - Photographs and Slides, 1986 (Box-folder 205/10)
    - Progress Report, 1987 (Box-folder 241/7)
    - Progress Reports, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 205/11)
    - Progress Reports and Related Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 205/12)
    - Promotional Photography, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 205/13)
    - Public Access Road, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 205/14-15)
    - Public Access Road, Permit, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 206/1)
    - Public Land Access Association, Incorporated, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 206/2)
    - Publicity, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 206/3)
    - Ranch Property, Real Estate Reports, 1989 (Box-folder 206/4)
    - Ranch Management Committee, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 206/5)
    - Ranch Management Committee, Correspondence, Memoranda, and Reports, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 206/6)
    - Ranch Manager Position, 1987 (Box-folder 206/7)
    - Elmer E. Rasmuson, 2001 (Box-folder 225/5)
    - Reports and Updates, 1994 (Box-folder 206/8)
    - Reproduction of Printed Materials, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 206/9)
    - Research and Reports, 1996-2005 (Box-folder 225/4)
    - Research Program and Professorship, 1985 (Box-folder 206/10)
    - Research Station, Wildlife/Agricultural Management Project, Pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 206/11)
    - Salmon Ranch, Teton County, Montana, Appraisal Report, 1984 (Box-folder 206/12)
    - William L. Searle, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 206/13)
    - Stationary, Originals, 1992 (Box-folder 206/14)
    - Strategic Plan, 1999 (Box-folder 206/15)
    - Strategic Planning, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 206/16)
    - Tax Assessment, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 206/17)
    - Theodore Roosevelt Association, Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 206/18)
    - Triple Divide Ranch, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 206/19)
    - Triple Divide Ranch, Appraisal Report, 1984 (Box-folder 207/1)
    - University of Montana Research, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 207/2-4)
    - Wildlife Ranch Management Project, Pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 207/5)
    - Workshop, Correspondence and Reports, 1986 (Box-folder 207/6)
  - University of Montana Applied Research Program and Professorship, 1985-1996; Subseries 4; 0.5 linear feet
    In 1987 the Club entered into a collaboration with The University of Montana to establish and direct research programs at the Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Ranch. In addition, a Boone and Crockett Wildlife Professorship was established at the university.
    This subseries contains the agreement with The University of Montana, correspondence, reports, and miscellaneous materials.
    - Boone and Crockett Professor's Report on Wildlife Congress, undated (Box-folder 207/7)
    - Boone and Crockett Professorship at The University of Montana, Agreement, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 207/8)
    - Boone and Crockett Professorship at The University of Montana, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1991 (Box-folder 207/9)
    - Boone and Crockett Professorship at The University of Montana, Hiring Committee, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1991 (Box-folder 207/10)
    - Boone and Crockett Professorship at The University of Montana, Memoranda and Reports, 1995 (Box-folder 207/11)
    - Boone and Crockett Professorship at The University of Montana, Press Releases, 1985 and undated (Box-folder 207/12)
    - Conservation Education Program, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1996 (Box-folder 207/13)
    - The University of Montana, Boone and Crockett, Wildlife Conservation Program, 1993 (Box-folder 207/14)
    - The University of Montana, Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 208/1)
    - The University of Montana, Miscellaneous Materials, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 208/2)
    - Wildlife Conservation Program, Final Report of Forestry 595, 1993 (Box-folder 208/3)
  - Financial and Fundraising, 1983-1998; Subseries 5; 3.0 linear feet
    This subseries documents the fundraising activities of the Foundation. Included are audit materials, correspondence, donation reports, grant materials, financial documents, and tax materials.
    - Action Lists, 1986 (Box-folder 208/4)
    - Action Lists, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 208/5)
    - American Petroleum Institute, Correspondence, 1985 (Box-folder 208/6)
    - Annual Foundation Dinner, Attendants List, 1987 (Box-folder 208/7)
    - Annual Foundation Dinner, Menu, 1994 (Box-folder 208/8)
    - Audit, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 208/9)
    - Audit, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 208/10)
    - Audited Statements, 1988 (Box-folder 208/11)
    - Audited Statements, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 208/12)
    - Audited Year-End Statement, Club/Depot/Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 208/13)
    - Auditor's Report and Financial Statements, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 208/14)
    - Boeing Company, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 209/1)
    - Budget, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 209/2)
    - Budget, Expense Reports, and Financial Statements, Fiscal Year 1996, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 209/3-5)
    - Budget, Expense Reports, and Financial Statements, Fiscal Year 1997, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 209/6-9)
    - California Funding Prospects, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 210/1)
    - Oscar Carlson, Expense and Fund Reports, 1988 (Box-folder 210/2)
    - Champion International, 1986 (Box-folder 210/3)
    - Charitable Giving Mailer, 1998 (Box-folder 210/4)
    - Complied Financial Statements and Accountants' Compilation Report, 1988 (Box-folder 210/5)
    - Donation Acknowledgement Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 210/6)
    - Donation and Expense Cover Memorandum, 1988 (Box-folder 210/7)
    - Donation and Financial Documents, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 210/8)
    - Donation and Pledge List, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 210/9)
    - Donation Records, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 210/10)
    - Donation Records, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 210/11)
    - Donation Records, 1991 (Box-folder 210/12)
    - Donation Records, 1992 (Box-folder 210/13)
    - Donation Records, 1993 (Box-folder 211/1)
    - Donation Records, 1994 (Box-folder 211/2)
    - Donation Records, 1995 (Box-folder 211/3)
    - Donations and Expenses, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 211/4-6)
    - Donations Committee, Correspondence, Memoranda, and Reports, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 211/7-8)
    - Donations Committee Steering Group, Correspondence and Meeting Materials, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 211/9)
    - Expense Reports and Invoices, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 212/1)
    - Expense Reports and Summaries, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 212/2-3)
    - Financial Reports, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 212/4)
    - Financial Reports, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 212/5)
    - Financial Statements, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 212/6)
    - Financial Statements, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 212/7)
    - Frick Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1987 (Box-folder 212/8)
    - Funding Prospect List, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 212/9)
    - Fundraising, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 212/10)
    - Fundraising Action, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 213/1)
    - Fundraising, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1995 (Box-folder 213/2)
    - Gates Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 213/3)
    - Fisher Howe Fundraising Articles, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 213/4)
    - Individual Donors, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 213/5)
    - Kleberg Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1987 (Box-folder 213/6)
    - Mazuri Wildlife Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1987 (Box-folder 213/7)
    - Member Donations, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 213/8)
    - Minnesota Funding Prospects, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 213/9)
    - Model 21 Winchester Auction, Member Mailer, Drafts, 1991 (Box-folder 213/10)
    - National Forest Foundation, Grant-in-Aid Materials, 1995 (Box-folder 213/11)
    - Nature Conservancy Grant, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 213/12)
    - North American Wild Sheep Foundation, Correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 213/13)
    - Northwest Area, Materials, 1995 (Box-folder 213/14)
    - Potential Funding Sources, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 213/15-16)
    - Proposal Rejections, 1987 (Box-folder 214/1)
    - Proposals, Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 214/2)
    - Proposed Budget, 1986 and undated (Box-folder 214/3)
    - Rating Committee and Donation Committee, 1986 (Box-folder 214/4-5)
    - Richard King Mellon Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 214/6)
    - Ruger Rifle Raffle, 1988 (Box-folder 214/7)
    - Scriver Bronze, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 214/8)
    - Tax Exempt Status and other Tax Forms, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 214/9)
    - Tax Return, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 214/10)
    - Tax Return, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 214/11)
    - Tax Return, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 214/12)
    - Tax Status, 1986 (Box-folder 214/13)
    - W. Alton Jones Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 214/14)
    - William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, Correspondence and Proposal, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 214/15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-1991; Subseries 6; 0.25 linear feet
    - Articles for Bulletins, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 214/16)
    - Montana Land Reliance, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 214/17)
    - Petersen's Hunting Article, 1988 (Box-folder 214/18)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 214/19)
    - The New Western Frontier, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 214/20)
    - Welder Wildlife Foundation Visit, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 214/21)
- Unprocessed Audio and Video Material, Series VI
  This series contains audiocassettes and VHS tapes that have not yet been identified.
  - Audiocassettes (Box 216)
  - VHS Tapes (Box 231-233)
- George Bird Grinnell Manuscripts, circa 1885-1910; Series VII; 0.2 linear feet
  This series consists of handwritten and typescript material produced by George Bird Grinnell and purchased from a manuscript dealer for the Boone and Crockett Club in 1999. The material is currently retained in its original notebook from the dealer.
  - Notebook of George Bird Grinnell typescripts and hand written documents, Most content was likely created by Grinnell, but the lot also includes several manuscripts clearly by others - likely intended as submissions to Forest and Stream. (Box 253)